<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ux on Brian M Hunt</title>
    <link>https://brianmhunt.github.io/tags/ux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ux on Brian M Hunt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brianmhunt.github.io/tags/ux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinionated modals with Knockout</title>
      <link>https://brianmhunt.github.io/post/2014-09-16-opinionated-modals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brianmhunt.github.io/post/2014-09-16-opinionated-modals/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s this? Highly opinionated modals to achieve a user experience I like:
 Demonstration; Repository.  Why&amp;rsquo;s it matter? It makes an impression, works with, and demonstrates interesting things in HTML5, Javascript ES6, CSS3 and Knockout.js.
What does it do? There are a few problems Knockout Modal tackles, including:
 Modals longer than the viewport height Nesting of modals Concise code (~100 line of Javascript) Happily integrates with code for HTML5 history Accepts thenables (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of typography</title>
      <link>https://brianmhunt.github.io/post/2014-01-24-importance-of-typography/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brianmhunt.github.io/post/2014-01-24-importance-of-typography/</guid>
      <description>You have no doubt thought about the font you use to communicate your written words. In the absence of any particular insight or authority you have likely chosen a common font such as Times New Roman or Arial or Helvetica. You have probably wondered whether this choice has any impact on the outcome of your written communication. The answer is a definitive yes — the form a writing takes substantially affects the message read, though as we will discuss below it is not just limited to the choice of font.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permanent HTTP caching and busting</title>
      <link>https://brianmhunt.github.io/post/2014-01-23-permanent-caching-and-busting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brianmhunt.github.io/post/2014-01-23-permanent-caching-and-busting/</guid>
      <description>What is it? Permanent caching is part of the HTTP protocol, a way to reduce server load and improve the user experience by speeding up load time.
Why does it matter? Caches make us and users happy. We get less load on our servers, and it&amp;rsquo;s a significant speedup for load times.
The busting is important because without it the resource may not be downloaded by a browser even though it has been updated on the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asynchronous client-side Javascript page loading</title>
      <link>https://brianmhunt.github.io/post/2014-01-22-making-everything-async/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brianmhunt.github.io/post/2014-01-22-making-everything-async/</guid>
      <description>What is it? A process for loading our script resources asynchronously, with one &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; tag, like this:
&amp;lt;script async src=&amp;#39;/all.js-{{ cache_buster }}&amp;#39;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; This all.js file loads all our Javascript, external services, templates, and any RESTful resources from our server.
We discuss the cache_buster in the next post.
Why is it important? Having one file for Javascript gives us:
 one file to request; improved cachability; parallel requests for our resources; centralizing where we control our loading; fine-grained control of the loading process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>