<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Brian M Hunt</title>
    <link>https://brianmhunt.github.io/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Brian M Hunt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brianmhunt.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Google App Engine tags for ndb</title>
      <link>https://brianmhunt.github.io/post/2014-04-04-ndb-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brianmhunt.github.io/post/2014-04-04-ndb-tags/</guid>
      <description>What is it? This is a way to add tags functionality to classes derived from ndb.Model on Google App Engine by way of a mixin.
Why is it important? Adding tags to data models is a popular phenomenon, but there does not appear to be a published way to accomplish the common functionality with ndb. This method ought to be reusable and performant.
How does it work? Get the full gist is gist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storing passwords using Python</title>
      <link>https://brianmhunt.github.io/post/2014-01-25-strong-crypto-python-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brianmhunt.github.io/post/2014-01-25-strong-crypto-python-passwords/</guid>
      <description>What is it? An implementation in Python for storing passwords with cryptographically recognized techniques.
Why is it important? Stored passwords get disclosed from time to time. Good examples give us guidance and help us avoid mistakes.
Password disclosure is bad news for users and the authenticator. Worse it undermines the trust the public has in our systems for storing and accessing private, personal services.
When using cryptography it is possible that even if the values stored are disclosed that the secrets they reflect remain opaque, or at least cost ineffective to discover.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>